SANGEETA MENON

Information Developer — Technical Writer

 $(+91)9945313249 \diamond$ sangeeta.tw@gmail.com \diamond sangeetamenon.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Technical Writer with more than 16 years of experience in developing and managing technical information for engineering and software products, while working in various domains such as **Telecommunications**, **Networking**, and **Health Care**. Prior to that, I worked for more than 4 years in creating non-technical content for healthcare and shopping portals.

SKILLS

Technical Skills Basic understanding of programming in C/C++, Java, and Python

Markup Languages HTML, XML, Markdown (with Git and GitHub)

Authoring Tools Confluence Wiki, MS Word, Robohelp 8, Adobe Framemaker 10

Image Editing Tools Adobe Photoshop, Hypersnap, Snag IT, Microsoft Visio, Camtasia studio

Defect Tracking ToolJIRA, ClearQuestContent ManagementDocumentum, VSSStyle GuideMicrosoft Style Guide

Soft Skills SMEs Interviews, Multi-tasking, Problem Solving, Continuous Learning

EXPERIENCE

Ribbon Communications Principal Technical Writer

February 2014 - May 2020

6 years 3 months

- · **Products:** Session Border Controller (SBC), Signaling Gateway (SGX), DataStream Integrator (Server and Cloud).
- · Interviewed SMEs, researched, and developed high-quality documents such as Installation and Configuration guide, Upgrade guide, Feature guide, Alarms and Traps guide, REST API User guide, and Command-line Interface (CLI) guide.
- · Iterated and improved documents based on stakeholder feedback, using JIRA for issue tracking and resolution reports.
- · Created project plans, resource and effort estimates, reports for tracking project status and progress, team performance metrics.
- · Proactively identified risks and bottlenecks in workflow and publishing process.
- · Strategized, innovated, and implemented solutions to improve operational efficiency.
- · Contributed to editorial reviews, document aesthetics, style guide, internal knowledge base.
- · Developed training materials for new employees.
- \cdot Mentored junior writers to improve their knowledge and productivity.

IP Infusion Pvt. Ltd.

January 2013 - February 2014

Senior Technical Writer

1 year 2 months

- · Products: ZEBOS Network Platform, Aeroz Network Platform.
- · Planned and developed User guide, Installation guide, Configuration guide, API guide, and CLI guide.
- · Managed SME feedback, ensured document correctness and completeness.
- · Tested documents for clarity, readability, and user experience.
- · Created standardized templates, style guide, checklist, standards, guidelines, and procedures.
- · Assisted the Lead Quality Consultant in various QMS tasks for CMMi reassessments.

OnMobile Global Ltd.

March 2010 - December 2012

Technical Writer 2 years 9 months

- · **Products:** Mobile, Messaging, and Marketing unit (M3PU).
- · Planned, authored, reviewed, and improved Getting Started guide, Architecture guide, Training guide, User guide, Product Notes, Installation guide, API guide, Proposal documents, Product Brochures, Technical Support documents, and Release Notes.
- · Tested product GUIs for usability and user experience, .
- · Created aesthetically pleasing system diagrams for Software Architects.

Dynpro (for IBM)

Technical Writer

July 2008 - January 2010

1 year 7 months

- · Products: Nokia Siemens Network 4G.
- · Researched and developed User guide, Interface guide, Statistics guide, Command Line Interface (CLI) guide
- · Improved documents based on feedback from engineers, product managers, and customers.
- · Tested documents in development environments.

ArisGlobal Software Networks

December 2005 - March 2008

Senior Technical Writer

2 years 3 months

- · Products: Arisg, Agxchange, CTM, Communications.
- · Authored User guide, Admin guide, Installation guide, Database guide, and Online Help, while ensuring strict compliance with user documentation process.
- · Reviewed and formatted Functional Specification Documents (FSDs), Release Notes, Standardized Documentation Templates.

Other Experiences

- · Clinical Data Manager (May 2003 January 2005) at Pfizer India Ltd.
- · Catalogue Manager at e-officeplanet.com.
- · Content Specialist at Cyberspace Infosys Solutions.
- · Content Designer at Aptech Ltd.
- · Quality Assurance Professional at Raptokos Brett Co. Ltd.
- · Trainee Quality Assurance at Parke-Davis Ltd.

PROFESSIONAL RECOGNITION

Ribbon Communications

- · Accorded the title of "Role Model" during Performance Appraisal 2018.
- · Nominated for Individual Excellence award for initiating quality in documentation.
- · Received Spot award, Easy Button award.

OnMobile Global Ltd

· Received a 'Pat-in-back' award for achieving excellence in documentation.

EDUCATION

Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering Technology

Asset International

M.Sc Chemistry

Institute of Science